João de Maredo Borges

Porto, Portugal



hello@jbbmb.com



linkedin.com/in/jbbmb



https://jbbmb.com

Summary

Everyone around João knew he was meant to work with technology since 1997, the year he was born. After high school, he started his Bachelor's in Computer Sciences, got involved in numerous freelance projects and began experimenting with different industry roles. Over the years, he worked with insightful teams using a range of tools, such as Jira, and technologies, like Java. Recently, he grew a special attention to detail for Quality Control and Agile Processes, fell in love with User Experience and wants to learn more about SwiftUI and modern FrontEnd frameworks. One thing to remember about him is that he can make a mean gin and tonic.

Experience



Application Support Team Lead

BNP Paribas - Securities Services

Jan 2022 - Present (1 year 7 months)

João is now responsible for coordinating the Portuguese Team charged with maintaining NEOLINK one of the many BP2S' International SWIFT Transactional Systems - in Production.

Skills: Incident Management, IBM Cloud, ServiceNow, PL/SQL, SharePoint, SailPoint, Jira, Active Directory



System & Network Administrator

Plásticos Bueso II

Jun 2019 - Present (4 years 2 months)

From online presence, to order processing and security updates, João helps to maintain all of the IT infrastructure required to run his family's plastics injection business.

Skills: Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JavaScript, DNS Administration



Product & Quality Assurance Analyst

FOURSOURCE

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021 (1 year 3 months)

João took on the responsibility of joining this B2B startup's first line of Quality Control and his role was to transform expected behavioral requirements into fully decomposed, materialized and testable acceptance criteria, that go on to be developed in Go+Angular.

Skills: Software Quality, Product Management, Agile Methodologies, Jira, Unified Modeling Language (UML), Microservices

Software Developer

CPCIT4ALL

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

João's mission at this HR-focused company was to help during a critical transition to newer, web-based technologies. He was tasked with refining and re-implementing existing components, using mostly ASP.NET and pure JavaScript, to be re-used at a later stage.

Skills: C#, JavaScript, ASP.NET, .NET Framework

Software Developer

Celfocus

Apr 2018 - Jul 2018 (4 months)

This challenge involved refactoring a Spring-based Java corporate social network into a platform that could retain acquired skills by staff and match them to a new project, given its technical requirements. Skills: Java, Spring MVC

Education

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Sciences 2015 - Present

Externato Ribadouro

High School Diploma, Sciences and Technology 2012 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

Certificate of C2 Proficiency in English - Cambridge University Press & Assessment English
A4565478

Skills

Git • Maven • jQuery • Representational State Transfer (REST) • Final Cut Pro • Adobe Photoshop • WordPress • macOS • General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) • Public Speaking

Honors & Awards

1st ever "Cherry Pick Porto" Staff - Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática do ISEP Jun 2016